<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tourism>
<municipality><title>Boac Cathedral</title><image>boac1.jpg</image><content>The Simbahan ng Boac or Boac Cathedral built in 1792 in Boac, Marinduque.&#13;
&#13;
The Cathedral was built in honor of Birhen ng Biglang Awa, who the locals consider as their defender from the pirate attacks in the 18th century. The location of the Cathedral at the highest point of the town and its structure as a fortress church was able to protect and secure the town and its people.&#13;
&#13;
Standing for more than two hundred years and serving as a witness to the long history of Marinduque, the Boac Cathedral was recognized as an Important Cultural Property by the National Museum in 2018.</content></municipality><municipality><title>Buenavista Church</title><image>buena1.jpg</image><content>Holy Child Jesus of the Roman Catholic Diocese of Boac was established on 1954. It is located in Brgy. the Municipality of Buenavista, Province of Marinduque. The Parish Fiesta is celebrated every 19th day of January. </content></municipality><municipality><title>Gasan Church</title><image>gasan1.jpg</image><content>Gasan is one of the municipalities that comprise the island province of Marinduque.  It is right next to  the municipality of Boac. My trip to Gasan was unforgettable because of this beautiful church again, located on top of a hill, overlooking the vast blue ocean (I don’t know if it’s West Philippine Sea or Pacific Ocean.)Going to the church is a bit of a challenge. You could go either climb the stairs or ride a vehicle all the way to the top.  Which way you choose, reaching the top is worth the climb.</content></municipality><municipality><title>Mogpog Church</title><image>mogpog1.jpg</image><content>San Isidro Labrador Parish of the Roman Catholic Diocese of Boac was established on 1807. It is located in the Municipality of Mogpog, Province of Marinduque. The Parish Fiesta is celebrated every 15th day of May. </content></municipality><municipality><title>Torrijos Church</title><image>torri1.jpg</image><content>St. Ignatius of Loyola Parish of the Roman Catholic Diocese of Boac was established on 1880. It is located in the Municipality of Torrijos, Province of Marinduque. The Parish Fiesta is celebrated every 31st day of July.</content></municipality><municipality><title>Santa Cruz Church</title><image>stacruz1.jpg</image><content>Holy Cross Parish of the Roman Catholic Diocese of Boac was established on 1609. It is located in Brgy. Sta. Cruz, Municipality of Sta. Cruz, Province of Marinduque. The Parish Fiesta is celebrated every 3rd Day of May.</content></municipality></tourism>
